[Sharp Blade in the Snow]
[نصل حاد في الثلج]
[Episode 7] Support Admin Watch on kissasia.cam or kisskh.org
[الحلقة 7] دعم الإدارة. شاهد على kissasia.cam أو kisskh.org
I've always been like this.
لطالما كنتُ هكذا.
No need for your comments.
لا داعي لتعليقاتك.
Your Majesty.
جلالة الملك.
Princess Royal has prepared
الأميرة آن قد استعدت
esculent swift's nest soup for you.
حساء عش السنونو اللذيذ لك.
I heard some noise outside just now,
سمعت بعض الضوضاء في الخارج الآن،
and in my urgency,
وفي ظلّ إلحاحي،
I rushed in.
اندفعت إلى الداخل.
Li.
الذي - التي.
I am worried
أنا قلق
that you might do something foolish.
حتى لا تفعل شيئاً أحمق.
Mr. Bai,
السيد باي،
today is Li's birthday.
اليوم هو عيد ميلاد لي.
You shouldn't make her angry.
لا يجب أن تغضبها.
Li is still a little girl.
لي لا تزال طفلة صغيرة.
Now she is seeking pleasure.
إنها الآن تبحث عن المتعة.
But she will settle down eventually.
لكنها ستستقر في النهاية.
I was impulsive.
كنت مندفعًا.
Sorry for my improper behavior.
أعتذر عن سلوكي غير اللائق.
I'll take my leave now.
سأغادر الآن.
Aunt, you won't blame me for being willful, right?
يا خالتي، لن تلوميني على عنادي، أليس كذلك؟
Indulging in pleasure in youth
الانغماس في الملذات في سن الشباب
is common.
هذا شائع.
But you need to take care of yourself.
لكن عليك أن تعتني بنفسك.
If you truly like him,
إذا كنتِ معجبة به حقاً،
just have him serve you every day.
اجعله يخدمك كل يوم.
Aunt, you love me so much.
يا عمتي، أنتِ تحبينني كثيراً.
Li.
الذي - التي.
For you, I am willing to do anything.
أنا على استعداد لفعل أي شيء من أجلك.
I hope you
أتمنى أن
understand my good intentions.
افهموا نواياي الحسنة.
Mr. Bai.
السيد باي.
Princess Royal requests your presence.
تطلب الأميرة الملكية حضوركم.
Your Majesty, you truly have foresight,
يا صاحب الجلالة، لديك حقاً بعد نظر.
knowing Princess Royal would come
مع العلم أن الأميرة الملكية ستأتي
to check on your whereabouts.
للتحقق من مكان وجودك.
But your health...
لكن صحتك...
It's nothing.
لا شئ.
Where's the box?
أين الصندوق؟
My mother left me
تركتني أمي
a piece of black jade.
قطعة من اليشم الأسود.
Black jade.
اليشم الأسود.
It turns out the most important thing
اتضح أن أهم شيء
has been with me all along.
لقد كان معي طوال الوقت.
This is your pendant,
هذا هو قلادتك،
a keepsake from your mother?
تذكار من والدتك؟
Yes.
نعم.
Years ago, when I was secretly banished to the wasteland,
قبل سنوات، عندما نُفيت سراً إلى أرض قاحلة،
I treasured it as my life.
لقد اعتززت بها كما لو كانت حياتي.
Later, I gave it to
ثم أعطيته لـ
a particularly important friend.
صديق مهم للغاية.
Now it is returned,
والآن تم إرجاعه،
but that person...
لكن ذلك الشخص...
Your Majesty,
جلالة الملك،
you were banished to the wasteland for years,
لقد نُفيت إلى الأرض القاحلة لسنوات،
but no one knew.
لكن لم يكن أحد يعلم.
On the wasteland in the eastern suburbs,
في الأراضي القاحلة في الضواحي الشرقية،
there was a Phoenix Mountain
كان هناك جبل فينيكس
with 1,361 dead trees.
مع 1361 شجرة ميتة.
I guarded them for a full ten years.
لقد حرسْتُهم لمدة عشر سنوات كاملة.
The wasteland in the eastern suburbs.
الأراضي القاحلة في الضواحي الشرقية.
Phoenix Mountain.
جبل فينيكس.
If the young lady
إذا كانت الشابة
leaves the water now,
يغادر الماء الآن،
not only will it fail to clear
لن يفشل فقط في التطهير
the toxins in her body,
السموم الموجودة في جسدها،
but it will worsen the damp poison inside her.
لكن ذلك سيزيد من سوء حالة السم الرطب بداخلها.
I'm afraid
أخشى
she won't survive three days.
لن تصمد ثلاثة أيام.
Unless...
إلا إذا...
Don't move.
.لا تتحرك
What are you doing?
ماذا تفعل؟
I want to save you.
أريد أن أنقذك.
This is insubordination.
هذا عصيان.
Aren't you afraid I'll punish you?
ألا تخشى أن أعاقبك؟
I'm not afraid.
أنا لست خائفا.
If you were to die, Your Majesty,
لو متّ يا جلالة الملك،
that would be the greatest punishment for me.
سيكون ذلك أشد عقاب لي.
Let go.
اتركه.
What are you doing?
ماذا تفعل؟
I
أنا
want you to live.
أريدك أن تعيش.
You must survive.
يجب أن تنجو.
Stone King of Hell's inner strength is profound.
إن القوة الداخلية لملك الجحيم الحجري عميقة.
If you want her to survive,
إذا كنت تريدها أن تنجو،
use your extremely strong Yang energy
استخدم طاقة اليانغ القوية للغاية لديك
to neutralize the cold poison in her body
لتحييد سم البرد في جسدها
and then transfer half of the poison
ثم انقل نصف السم
into your body.
إلى جسمك.
Perhaps
ربما
there might still be a chance of survival.
قد لا تزال هناك فرصة للنجاة.
Let go.
اتركه.
No.
لا.
Thanks, Your Highness.
شكراً يا صاحب السمو.
You're too kind to me.
أنت لطيف جداً معي.
Mr. Bai, you're Prime Minister Bai's only son.
السيد باي، أنت الابن الوحيد لرئيس الوزراء باي.
Three generations of the Bai family have served Mocheng loyally.
خدمت ثلاثة أجيال من عائلة باي مدينة موتشنغ بإخلاص.
You deserve it.
أنت تستحق ذلك.
You've cared for Li since childhood.
لقد اعتنيت بلي منذ طفولته.
I've known it all.
لقد كنت أعرف كل شيء.
But today,
لكن اليوم،
you've truly been quite improper.
لقد تصرفت بشكل غير لائق تماماً.
Mr. Bai comes from a prestigious family.
ينتمي السيد باي إلى عائلة مرموقة.
You are elegant and handsome.
أنت أنيق ووسيم.
Besides, you and the Queen are childhood sweethearts.
إلى جانب ذلك، أنت والملكة حبيبان منذ الطفولة.
However, now Mr. Bai is outside,
لكن السيد باي الآن في الخارج.
while Yun Zhan is on her bed.
بينما يون زان مستلقية على سريرها.
I even feel sorry
بل أشعر بالأسف.
for you.
لك.
I have
أملك
no jealousy.
لا غيرة.
But the Queen is frail.
لكن الملكة ضعيفة.
If she indulges in pleasure daily,
إذا انغمست في الملذات يومياً،
I fear it will harm her health.
أخشى أن يضر ذلك بصحتها.
Mr. Bai, you're truly attentive.
السيد باي، أنت حقاً شديد الانتباه.
You're concerned about Li's health.
أنت قلق بشأن صحة لي.
Among all men in the world,
من بين جميع رجال العالم،
only you
أنت فقط
truly care for Li.
أنا أهتم حقاً بـ لي.
Thank you, Your Highness.
شكراً لك يا صاحب السمو.
But do you know
لكن هل تعلم؟
why Li is in poor health?
لماذا يعاني لي من اعتلال صحته؟
Li
الذي - التي
has been poisoned.
لقد تعرض للتسمم.
What?
ماذا؟
Yes,
نعم،
I did it all.
لقد فعلت كل شيء.
If you want to save her,
إذا كنت تريد إنقاذها،
you might hear my conditions.
قد تسمع شروطي.
Trade the formula of Phoenix Incense
استبدل تركيبة بخور فينيكس
for Feng Li's antidote.
للحصول على ترياق فينغ لي.
And persuade Li to take her poor health as an excuse
وأقنع لي بأن تتخذ من سوء حالتها الصحية عذراً.
to abdicate.
التنازل عن العرش.
Then I'll ensure you and Li
سأضمن لك ولي ذلك.
remain together forever.
سنبقى معاً إلى الأبد.
Your future
مستقبلك
depends on you.
الأمر يعتمد عليك.
Your Highness,
صاحب السمو،
this move
هذه الخطوة
is quite risky.
إنه أمر محفوف بالمخاطر.
Bai Yu is pure and innocent,
باي يو نقي وبريء،
and completely devoted to Feng Li.
ومُكرّسة تماماً لفنغ لي.
So, Feng Li's life for him
إذن، حياة فنغ لي بالنسبة له
is our greatest leverage.
إنها أكبر نقاط قوتنا.
Aren't you afraid
ألا تخاف؟
Bai Yu will report this to Feng Li?
هل سيبلغ باي يو فنغ لي بهذا الأمر؟
Who would believe him?
من سيصدقه؟
Don't you
أنت , لا
agree?
يوافق؟
Master, let me serve you to bathe.
سيدي، دعني أخدمك للاستحمام.
[Wutong Palace]
[قصر ووتونغ]
Now that we meet again,
والآن وقد التقينا مجدداً،
you've become my enemy.
لقد أصبحت عدوي.
It's ironic.
إنه لأمر مثير للسخرية.
Back then, you were just a child,
في ذلك الوقت، كنت مجرد طفل،
enduring the same suffering
تحمل نفس المعاناة
as I did in the wasteland.
كما فعلت في الأرض القاحلة.
There must be something fishy behind
لا بد أن هناك شيئاً مريباً وراء ذلك.
the feud between Dongli and Mocheng.
الخلاف بين دونغلي وموتشنغ.
You're awake.
أنت مستيقظ.
How are you feeling?
كيف تشعر؟
Are you better now?
هل أنت بخير الآن؟
How dare you make decisions on your own?
كيف تجرؤ على اتخاذ القرارات بمفردك؟
What are you smiling about?
ما الذي يجعلك تبتسم؟
Savoring last night's pleasure,
مستمتعاً بمتعة الليلة الماضية،
I feel joyful inside.
أشعر بالفرح في داخلي.
Your Majesty,
جلالة الملك،
Princess Royal has sent me to deliver medicine.
أرسلتني الأميرة الملكية لتوصيل الدواء.
Your Majesty, don't be shy.
جلالتك، لا تخجل.
We must continue with this charade.
يجب أن نستمر في هذه المهزلة.
You're becoming increasingly disrespectful.
أنت تزداد قلة احتراماً.
Do you want to watch me in this way?
هل تريد أن تشاهدني بهذه الطريقة؟
I dare not.
لا أجرؤ.
I didn't know you hadn't...
لم أكن أعلم أنك لم تفعل...
Indeed.
بالفعل.
Aunt always cares for me the most.
خالتي هي دائماً الأكثر اهتماماً بي.
Yes, Your Majesty,
نعم يا جلالة الملك،
the medicine should be taken while warm.
ينبغي تناول الدواء وهو دافئ.
Good medicine tastes bitter.
الدواء الجيد طعمه مر.
Let me try another way
دعني أجرب طريقة أخرى
to feed you, okay?
لإطعامك، حسناً؟
I'll take my leave now.
سأغادر الآن.
Are you crazy?
هل أنت مجنون؟
The medicine is poisoned.
الدواء مسموم.
With so many people watching,
مع وجود الكثير من الناس يشاهدون،
someone has to drink
لا بد أن يشرب أحدهم
this poison, right?
هذا السم، أليس كذلك؟
Self-sacrifice won't work on me.
لن يجدي التضحية بالنفس نفعاً معي.
Then, is this
إذن، هل هذا هو؟
enough to show my sincerity?
هل هذا كافٍ لإظهار صدقي؟
This was mine to begin with.
كان هذا ملكي في الأصل.
How can you give something away
كيف يمكنك أن تتخلى عن شيء ما؟
and then take it back?
ثم استعادته؟
Aren't you afraid your old friend to be heartbroken?
ألا تخشى أن ينكسر قلب صديقك القديم؟
I can't let others take notice of him.
لا يمكنني السماح للآخرين بالاهتمام به.
If he's still alive,
إذا كان لا يزال على قيد الحياة،
it could put him in danger.
قد يعرضه ذلك للخطر.
What old friend?
أي صديق قديم؟
That's all in the past.
كل ذلك أصبح من الماضي.
For me,
لي،
what matters is this black jade
المهم هو هذا اليشم الأسود
and the position of the queen.
ومنصب الملكة.
Indeed.
بالفعل.
With the black jade,
مع اليشم الأسود،
the next step
الخطوة التالية
is to get the Phoenix Incense.
الهدف هو الحصول على بخور العنقاء.
When the day comes to deliver the incense,
عندما يحين يوم تسليم البخور،
if you can't provide it,
إذا لم تتمكن من توفيره،
your position
موقعك
will be in jeopardy.
سيكونون في خطر.
Within three days,
في غضون ثلاثة أيام،
if we can prove that the Slave House incident
إذا استطعنا إثبات أن حادثة بيت العبيد
was not caused by the slaves,
لم يكن ذلك بسبب العبيد،
then there's no rush to deliver the incense.
إذن لا داعي للعجلة في توصيل البخور.
Those in the Slave House
أولئك الذين في بيت العبيد
are mostly obedient and timid.
هم في الغالب مطيعون وخجولون.
How could they suddenly rebel and riot?
كيف استطاعوا فجأة أن يتمردوا ويثيروا الشغب؟
Is that credible to you?
هل هذا الكلام يبدو لك معقولاً؟
Of course not.
بالطبع لا.
I agree.
أنا موافق.
[Slave House]
[بيت العبيد]
These female officials died horribly,
لقيت هؤلاء المسؤولات حتفهن بطريقة مروعة،
and all their blood drained.
ونُزف دمهم كله.
Look at the wounds on her face.
انظر إلى الجروح على وجهها.
They appear to be caused by clubs or sticks.
يبدو أن سببها هو الهراوات أو العصي.
On her neck,
على رقبتها،
there's a fatal wound
هناك جرح قاتل
pierced by a sharp weapon.
اخترقها سلاح حاد.
There are also wounds on her palms.
كما توجد جروح على راحتي يديها.
But why
لكن لماذا؟
was she stabbed?
هل تعرضت للطعن؟
It could be revenge.
قد يكون ذلك انتقاماً.